<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I&#39;m Stine on Stinelykkeolsen</title>
    <link>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in I&#39;m Stine on Stinelykkeolsen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> What do I do as a Technical Writer?</title>
      <link>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/technicalwriter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/technicalwriter/</guid>
      <description>In short, my role as a technical writer is to communicate technical information to various audiences.
As a tech writer I use a variety of tools in my day-to-day work to convey information to the end user in an applicable and comprehensible way. These tools include version control systems, XML’s, and text processing programs, such as GitHub, DITA XML, and Microsoft Word.
My experience with technical communication consists of writing, editing, and translating technical SEO web content, software and hardware documentation, user manuals, grant proposals, and other types of information.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;In short, my role as a technical writer is to communicate technical information to various audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a tech writer I use a variety of tools in my day-to-day work to convey information to the end user in an applicable and comprehensible way. These tools include version control systems, XML’s, and text processing programs, such as GitHub, DITA XML, and Microsoft Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience with technical communication consists of writing, editing, and translating technical SEO web content, software and hardware documentation, user manuals, grant proposals, and other types of information. My areas of expertise as a tech writer are software, science, hardware, and medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the services that I offer are technical writing and editing, coding, user experience design, and data analysis. I provide companies and organizations with, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; User manuals 
&amp;gt; Product descriptions
&amp;gt; Installation guides 
&amp;gt; Fact sheets
&amp;gt; Category texts
&amp;gt; Technical SEO web content
&amp;gt; Grant proposals
&amp;gt; Software documentation
&amp;gt; UX Writing
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deliver optimal results I may conducts interviews with developers, product owners, designers, and others. My strength as a skilled technical writer is a comprehensive technical knowledge combined with strong writing skills. This enables me to serve as link between experts and developers on the one hand and end users and audiences on the other hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-approach-to-technical-writing&#34;&gt;My Approach to Technical Writing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Docs like Code. Structured Writing. ASD-STE100 Simplified Technical English. These are all terms that float around the field of technical writing. Each of these terms cover different methods applied and practiced by tech writers. Each method has its merits and strengths depending on the subject matter of the content, the end user, the scope of the content, and the values and guidelines of the company or organization behind the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a tech writer I am flexible regarding the methods based on the nature of the task at hand. Regardless of the methods, my approach to technical writing is based on four pragmatic rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. Keep the end user in mind – a tech writer should be the reader’s advocate 
2. Stay true to the values, mission, and internal guidelines of the sender
3. Keep it clear – explain one aspect at the time in a clear language
4. Technical texts can still be enjoyable - even though the topics are complex 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I always strive to deliver well written, great technical content that focuses on the needs of the end user without loosing sight of the goals of the sender organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tools-and-technologies&#34;&gt;Tools and technologies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tech writer applies various tools when producing documentation and other types of text. I have experience with the following technologies and programming languages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; Git and GitHub
&amp;gt; DITA XML
&amp;gt; Memsource (and other CAT Tools)
&amp;gt; Microsoft Word
&amp;gt; Microsoft Access 
&amp;gt; Markdown
&amp;gt; VS Code
&amp;gt; Hugo
&amp;gt; JavaScript
&amp;gt; Python (Including PyCharm and Anaconda)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bio</title>
      <link>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/bio/</guid>
      <description>My journey towards becoming a technical writer and translator started in 2005 when I had my first job editing and proof reading a translation for a Danish First Aid Company. For the last couple of decades I have worked as a translator, writer, and language teacher. In 2022, however, I decided to take the leap and become an independent technical writer and translator.
My goal is to help companies and organizations optimize their technical communication by providing great technical content.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;My journey towards becoming a technical writer and translator started in 2005 when I had my first job editing and proof reading a translation for a Danish First Aid Company. For the last couple of decades I have worked as a translator, writer, and language teacher. In 2022, however, I decided to take the leap and become an independent technical writer and translator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal is to help companies and organizations optimize their technical communication by providing great technical content. In my personal and professional life I strive to adhere to my core values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Be quality conscious

# Be reliable and trustworthy

# Be genuine, respectful, and kind
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have successfully helped companies and organizations in the health software, first aid, educational, and technical hardware sectors with technical writing and translation tasks. They include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; Proof reading, editing, and quality management

&amp;gt; Communication strategy and planning

&amp;gt; SEO and technical copywriting

&amp;gt; Translation of medical software

&amp;gt; Subtitling 

&amp;gt; Hardware documentation

&amp;gt; Proposal writing for EU projects
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formally, I hold a master’s degree in Chinese and German Studies, and I have spent years teaching and translating these languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a tech writer, however, I mostly work with the language combination English – Danish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am not trying to coordinate the chaotic hubbub that is everyday life with a husband and two children, I am an avid practitioner of aikido, archery, and open water swimming.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clients and Certificates</title>
      <link>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/resume/</guid>
      <description>This page provides you with a short overview of my former and current clients.
I have also added a list of recent certificates in the technical field.
For a full overview of my education, certificates, and employment history, check out my resume on LinkedIn.
&amp;gt; KompetenceKanalen A/S&amp;gt; Semantix &amp;gt; TransPerfect &amp;gt; Intertranslations S.A.&amp;gt; Avantigruppen A/S&amp;gt; Bitmatic ApS.&amp;gt; Danmarks RadioCertifications &amp;gt; SDK Bridge: Coding for Writers: Basic Programming&amp;gt; SDK Bridge: Git and GitHub for Writers&amp;gt; JPDocu School of Technical Writing: How to Write Using DITA XML&amp;gt; JPDocu School of Technical Writing: Technical Writing: Getting Started with Python&amp;gt; Janet Underwood: Tech Writers Master Class&amp;gt; Viktor Garske:	Markdown für Einsteiger	&amp;gt; Google: Fundamentals of Digital Marketing	</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;This page provides you with a short overview of my former and current clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also added a list of recent certificates in the technical field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full overview of my education, certificates, and employment history, check out my resume on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/stinelykkeolsen/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; KompetenceKanalen A/S

&amp;gt; Semantix 

&amp;gt; TransPerfect 

&amp;gt; Intertranslations S.A.

&amp;gt; Avantigruppen A/S

&amp;gt; Bitmatic ApS.

&amp;gt; Danmarks Radio
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;certifications&#34;&gt;Certifications&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; SDK Bridge: Coding for Writers: Basic Programming

&amp;gt; SDK Bridge: Git and GitHub for Writers

&amp;gt; JPDocu School of Technical Writing: How to Write Using DITA XML

&amp;gt; JPDocu School of Technical Writing: Technical Writing: Getting Started with Python

&amp;gt; Janet Underwood: Tech Writers Master Class

&amp;gt; Viktor Garske:	Markdown für Einsteiger	

&amp;gt; Google: Fundamentals of Digital Marketing	
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Translation</title>
      <link>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/technicaltranslator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stinelykkeolsen.dk/technicaltranslator/</guid>
      <description>With the help of a skilled technical translator, you can brand your business through high quality translations. Professional technical translations ensure an accurate communication with international target audiences, enhance the user experience, and may in some cases even safeguard consumer safety.
In my role as technical translator, I translate articles, user manuals, software, web pages, and other technical content from German, Mandarin Chinese, and English into Danish.
I almost exclusively translate from the source language into my native language, Danish.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;With the help of a skilled technical translator, you can brand your business through high quality translations. Professional technical translations ensure an accurate communication with international target audiences, enhance the user experience, and may in some cases even safeguard consumer safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my role as technical translator, I translate articles, user manuals, software, web pages, and other technical content from German, Mandarin Chinese, and English into Danish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost exclusively translate from the source language into my native language, Danish. The exception is texts with simple syntax and grammar, such as software commands, UX texts, and simple user manuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the belief that no one understands a given language better than native speakers, this approach to translation is known as the Mother Tongue Principle. Applied by many organizations and translation professionals the principle is considered a cornerstone in securing the linguistical and cultural precision of a translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;localization--get-your-message-through-to-your-international-target-group&#34;&gt;Localization – get your message through to your international target group&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure you hit your mark with your audience it is not enough to translate your technical content word by word. Great translations also require cultural knowledge. This prevents that subtle linguistic differences between cultures and countries don’t disturb the meaning of the text or lead to misunderstandings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, cultural knowledge ensures that idioms and cultural references in the text are suitable for the target audience and makes reading your content more enjoyable for readers. This is called localization and it is one of the most important competences that a skilled translator must learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you hire an MA in Chinese and German studies like me not only do you get an expert in languages, translation, and communication. You also get a highly educated expert in Chinese and German culture and society, your guarantee for complete, well-balanced texts with a strong understanding for the target audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;high-quality-translations-are-a-matter-of-trust&#34;&gt;High quality translations are a matter of trust&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a technical translator I always comply with all formal rules and regulations regarding data safety. For the sake of data safety, copyrights, and the discretion of my employer or customers (and for the sake of the linguistic quality of the translation), I never use automatic translation tools, unless provided by my clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me the art of translation is more than simply translating the content of a text in a clear and comprehensible manner. The resulting target text should always be able to stand by itself as a complete text with its own life, so to speak. This often means that a translation is far from done after the first draft has been written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often the real work with creating great translations begins with the editing and proofreading phases. All translations that I produce go through a thorough quality management and proofreading before delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the text type, content, and end users, I may edit the text on various levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below, you see some elements of the text that I look at:
&amp;gt; Target group analysis: does the message of the text reach the target audience?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; Style: is the tone in accordance with the subject matter and target audience?

&amp;gt; Language: is the text clear, comprehensible, and nice to read?

&amp;gt; Mechanical style: are grammar, orthography, and punctuation spot on?

&amp;gt; Policy: is the text consistent with the vision and brand of your organization?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list could go on as there a of course many more levels of editing, depending on your needs and preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
